JEBA ROBERT

(+91) 9867100812

jebasalomi199835@gmail.com

Mumbai

in <u>linkedin.com/in/jeba-robert/</u>
github.com/jebarobert
iebarobert.github.io/my-portfolio

SUMMARY

Dedicated **DevOps engineer** with 5+ years of professional expertise, with a focus on DevOps using cloud platforms, DevOps tools, and Front-End tools.

Strongly driven and outcome-oriented leader who coaches teams of more than thirty employees on DevOps technologies. A devoted team player who is great at collaborating with others and who is focused on optimizing a facility's production process

♦ SKILLS

- DevOps/Automation: Ansible, AWX, Jenkins, Terraform, Gitlab, Gitlab CI, Jfrog Artifactory, Hashicorp Vault, Docker, Kubernetes, ServiceNow (workflows; forms; orchestration; NLU), Xray, Helm Charts
- Cloud: Azure(VM, EntralD, scalesets, storage account, virtual network, data factory, azure functions) AWS (EC2, VPC, S3, IAM), IBM Cloud (COS, Kubernetes & Containers)
- Scripting Languages: PowerShell, Python Scripting, Bash
- Front End: Angular JS, React JS
- Soft Skills: Research, Leadership, Mentorship, Presentation skills, Problem Solving
- Others: Rest API, DBMS, SQL, JavaScript

WORK EXPERIENCE

OCT 2024 - Present

Senior Associate (Tech Lead) | BNP Paribas | Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Designed and implemented robust continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD)
 pipelines using GitLab CI, enabling automated code testing, build, and deployment to multiple
 environments.
- Collaborated with development teams to optimize pipelines, reducing deployment times by 30% and ensuring seamless integration with containerized environments.
- integrated **SonarQube and Xray into the CI pipeline** to maintain high code quality and security standards, significantly reducing vulnerabilities.

AUG 2022 - OCT 2024

Consultant | Capgemini | Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Implemented 25+ high-impact automations in Ansible, Gitlab, Terraform, Jenkins, Docker and Kubernetes, delivered substantial efficiency improvements, resulting in the elimination of 500 Full Time Equivalent (FTE) hours monthly, boosting productivity and cost savings.
- Mentored a team of 15 members on Terraform and Provided Windows Automation for the first time in client environment
- Provided SIP by developing generic roles and documented the Automation with complete package
 of user manual, test results, flows and procedure

- Worked together with stakeholders to fully comprehend the aims and objectives of the project
- Designed dashboards for visualizing the automations using Angular JS and React JS
- Developed protocols to automate code deployments and builds in accordance with standards and guidelines, and effectively executed up to 70% of the automations systems automation using scripting languages like PowerShell and Python

JAN 2020 - AUG 2022

Engineer - Cloud & Infra Services | LTI | Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Identified and automated areas/categories in Azure saving minimum of 400 person hours.
- Worked closely with the operation teams to understand the requirement and creating new automation for service request to reduce the number of incidents.
- Worked with internal team, gathered requirements of client and did R&D for New IT Infrastructure automations which can help to automate the service request.
- Orchestrated ServiceNow using Ansible and Jenkins.
- Automated and deployed scripts in PowerShell to generate Reports on Weekly/Monthly Basis.



EDUCATION

June 2019 - May 2021

Master of Science in Information Technology | SIES | 93.4% (CGPA: 9.83) (Rank 1)

June 2016 - May 2019

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology | SIES | 82.65% (CGPA:8.7)



AWARDS

- **Delivery Excellence** Award (Capgemini) (2023)
- Won **Best Manager**'s Award from LTI CIS Academy (2021)
- Endowment Award First Rank in M.Sc. IT (2021)
- Geeta Israani Scholarship Award in TY (2019)



CERTIFICATIONS

- LTI Certified Cloud & Infrastructure Services Professional
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals
- Microsoft Certified: Microsoft Azure Administrator Associate
- Fundamentals of Database System (NPtel Online Certification) Percentage: 70%
- Demystifying Networking (NPtel Online Certification) Percentage: 78%
- Advanced Relational Database and SQL(Coursera) Grade Achieved: 90%
- Getting Started with Google Apps Script (Coursera) Grade Achieved: 100%
- Introduction to Python Scripting for DevOps (Coursera) Grade Achieved: 90%
- Getting Started with Azure DevOps Boards (Coursera)
- Containerization I/O Docker, Kubernetes, OpenShift (Coursera)